陪审团的女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
证据确凿  无可置疑
the evidence tells us well beyond a reasonable doubt
被告奥蒂斯·威廉斯是有罪的
that Otis Williams is guilty.
他射杀了莱拉·埃迪森
Now he shot and killed Lyla Addison.
动机为何
And for what?
就为了她的车  区区一辆车
For her car. Her car.
但威廉斯先生并未就此停止暴行
But that was not the end of Mr. Williams' savagery.
他把死者尸首扔进车尾箱后  驾车兜风
He tossed her body into a trunk and went on a joyride.
辩方纵然可以砌词狡辩
Now the defense can make up any stories they want,
却无法否定事实真相
but those stories do not negate the facts.
那就是威廉斯先生
And the facts are that Mr. Williams
是在死者车中遇捕
was caught in the victim's car,
车子布满他的指纹
his fingerprints were all over it,
他的衣服上沾有死者的血迹
and her blood was on his clothes.
真正的司法公正
The true administration of justice
乃善政的磐石之基
is the firmest foundation of good government.
本案将是对在座每一位的一次挑战
Now this should be a challenge to each and every one of you.
在座12位是这个世界上唯一
You are the 12 people in this world
能为莱拉·埃迪森伸张正义的人
that can bring justice to Lyla Addison.
救我
Help me.
-救我  -抱歉  先生  你不能...
- Help. - Excuse me, sir. You can't--
肃静
Order.
叫救护人员来
Call the paramedics.
你想谋杀亲子吗  里头放了什么啊
Are you trying to kill me? What's in this?
保你健康长寿的各种所需营养
Everything you need for a healthier and longer life.
要喝这种东西来延年益寿又有何意义
What is the sense of living longer if you have to drink that?
啊  健康全靠它了
Ahh. That's the stuff.
早啊
Good morning.
-早  宝贝  -嗨  你怎么还不去上学
- Good morning, darling. - Hey. Hey, why aren't you in school?
-今天是教师发展日  -好极了
- It's faculty development day. - Perfect,
因为你知道安吉里卡影城在放什么片吗
because do you know what's playing at the Angelika?
《禁忌星球》[经典科幻片]
"Forbidden Planet."
莱斯利·尼尔森主演  那时他还不是著名谐星
Leslie Nielsen, long before his comic glory.
你记得你有多爱这部片子吗
You remember how much you used to love this?
-咱俩一起去看吧  -抱歉  我去不了
- Want to go with me? Sorry, I can't.
我本就打算今天去格林威治村
I made plans to spend the day in the village.
很好喝  拜拜  奶奶
Delicious. Um, bye, grams.
-老爸再见  -再见
- Bye, dad. - Bye.
妈  你瞧见了吗  阿丽克西斯撒谎了
Mother, did you see that? Alexis lied.
她哪有  她不晓得多爱我的早餐特饮
She did not. She loves my breakfast smoothies.
不  我不是说这事
No, no, not about that.
她骗我们说今天要去村子
About where she's going today.
她皱了下鼻子  她一撒谎就会这样
Her nose crinkled. That's her tell.
亲爱的  别多疑了
Oh, honey, come on.
这又不是世界扑克锦标赛现场
This is not the World Series of Poker.
听我的没错  她肯定另有计划
I'm telling you, she's up to something.
那你呢  你想陪我去看电影吗
What about you? You want to go to the movies?
儿子  我也不行
No can do, kiddo.
我约了承包商在工作室见
Gotta meet with my contractor at the studio.
那看来我只能自己去了
Well, then it looks like I'm going by myself.
或许...
Or maybe...
不用去了
not at all.
找理查德·卡塞尔  请按1
For Richard Castle, press 1.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
为什么正门那么多新闻采访车
Why were there news vans out front?
因为本案的被害人是乔·麦丘茨克
Because of who our victim is Joe McUsic.
谁
Who?
莱拉·埃迪森一案的7号陪审员
Juror number seven in the Lyla Addison case.
埃迪森一案  说真的吗
The Addison case, seriously?
-出什么事了  -他在律师做结案陈词时猝死了
- What happened? - He dropped dead during the closing argument.
蕾妮认为他是被毒死的
Lanie thinks that he was poisoned.
埃迪森财团的继承人惨遭谋杀
Heir to the Addison Fortune is murdered,
然后此案的陪审员之一也在庭上被杀
and during the trial a juror is murdered as well.
这完全就是约翰·葛里逊小说里的情节
This has all the makings of a John Grisham novel.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在发短信给牌友  抢这则新闻的首发啊
I'm, uh, texting my poker group, calling dibs on this story.
他的确是被毒死的
He was poisoned, all right.
尸斑呈粉红色  尸体散发苦杏仁味
Pink lividity, the smell of bitter almonds--
试纸呈氰化物阳性反应
test strip came back positive for cyanide.
氰化物  太妙了
Cyanide? That is fantastic.
但对陪审员来说是晴天霹雳
Unless you're the juror.
尸体上没有任何刺孔
There were no puncture marks on the body,
毒物是经口摄入的
so it was ingested.
这样杀人太奇怪了
That's an odd way to kill.
对纳粹和邪恶的独裁者来说  不算怪
Not for Nazis or evil dictators.
他是怎么摄入的
How did he ingest it?
口腔内有褐色小点  说明他之前喝过咖啡
Brownish stains in his mouth indicate he recently had coffee.
也许咖啡里有毒
Maybe it was in there.
在他摄入毒物后  隔了多久才死亡
After he consumed the poison, how long before he died?
不多于15分钟
No more than 15 minutes.
据法庭书记员称
According to the court clerk,
麦丘茨克先生于今早8:37到达法庭
Mr. McUsic arrived this morning at 8:37
而后于9:13左右死亡
and died at approximately 9:13.
15分钟
15 minutes.
也就是说他是在法院内遭投毒的
That means that he was poisoned at the courthouse.
-陪审员死了  谁会得益  -被告
- And who benefits from a dead juror? - The defendant.
英雄所见略同
Then we agree.
被告是奥蒂斯·威廉斯
The defendant, Otis Williams.
这家伙是个无恶不作的混蛋
This guy's a real dirtbag's dirtbag.
特大汽车盗窃  恶性伤人  谋杀未遂
Grand theft auto, aggravated assault, attempted murder.
"三宗罪混蛋"  这就是说一旦罪名成立
Dirtbag trifecta, which means, if convicted,
-他得蹲很久牢房  -无期徒刑  不得假释
- he'd go away for a long time. - Life without parole.
如果纽约州还能执行死刑
I bet the D.A. would ask for the needle
地方检察官肯定会提出注射死刑
if New York still had the death penalty.
他们在失车上捉到他
They caught him in the stolen car
莱拉·埃迪森的尸体就在车尾箱里
with Lyla Addison's body in the trunk.
他们找到了他的指纹  死者的血迹
They got his fingerprints, traces of the victim's blood.
这家伙罪有攸归
This guy's way past guilty.
这才是恐吓陪审团的最佳手段
So this is jury intimidation at its finest.
你杀了陪审员  不仅能让审判无效
You kill a juror, you not only guarantee a mistrial,
还能杀鸡儆猴
but it also serves as a warning
借此恐吓今后重审的陪审员
for any future jurors on a retrial.
我意思是  如果当陪审员会招来
I mean, who wants to serve on a jury
杀身之祸  谁愿意当啊
if there's a chance of being killed?
但我们知道奥蒂斯不是凶手
But we know Otis didn't do it.
自他被捕后就一直处于监禁中
He's been incarcerated since his arrest.
他可能有同伙
He might have had an accomplice.
乔·麦丘茨克死前15分钟  就是在这栋楼里
Whoever poisoned Joe McUsic somehow did it in this building
遭凶手投毒的
15 minutes before he died.
我去找保安调出楼内所有走廊和
I'll get with security, pull the surveillance footage
公共休息室的监控录像带
from all the corridors and common rooms.
我去跟陪审员们谈谈  也许有人看到了什么
I'll talk to the jurors. Someone might have seen something.
好的
All right.
我们去问问奥蒂斯·威廉斯先生  看他怎么说吧
Why don't we see what Mr. Otis Williams has to say for himself?
辩方律师
Counselor.
我是贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
我想和你的当事人谈谈
I'd like to speak with your client.
探长  关于莱拉·埃迪森一案
Detective, anything we have to say about Lyla Addison,
要说的我们都在庭上说了
we've said during the trial.
我不是为埃迪森一案而来的
I'm not here about Ms. Addison.
我是为7号陪审员一案来的
I'm here about juror number seven.
好吧  他怎么了
Okay. What's about him?
-他是被谋杀的  -谋杀
- He was murdered. - Murdered?
我以为他是死于癫痫或是别的自然因素
I thought he died of a seizure or some other natural cause.
氰化物中毒可不是什么自然因素
There's nothing natural about cyanide poisoning.
听着  我的当事人对此一无所知
Okay, look, my client doesn't know anything about that,
我也绝不会允许你们问他话
and there's no way I'm letting him talk to you.
失陪  我们还要上庭
Now if you'll excuse us, we're due in court.
走吧
Let's go.
考虑到7号陪审员猝死
In light of the shocking circumstances
这一震惊的突发情况
of juror number seven's death,
本席相信参与本案的陪审团
it is my belief that this particular jury
已无法再作出公平的判决
is no longer capable of reaching a fair verdict.
故本席只能无奈宣告  本次审判无效
Therefore, I have no choice but to declare a mistrial.
法官阁下  原告将会再度提出指控
Uh, your honor, the people intend to refile charges.
记录在案
Noted.
在此之前  威廉斯将还押候审
Until then, Mr. Williams will be remanded.
本次听证会延期举行
This hearing is adjourned.
法官阁下  这能叫正义吗
You call this justice, your honor?
他可是杀了我女儿啊
After what he did to my daughter?
你...这个禽兽
You... Monster.
爸  爸  冷静
Dad! Dad, no.
我们回家
Let's go home.
看上去奥蒂斯的计划得逞了
Looks like Otis' plan is working.
嗯  到目前为止
Yeah, for now.
莱恩  你查到什么了吗
Ryan, you find anything yet?
暂时没有  那幢大楼里有很多个摄像头
Not yet. That building has a lot of cameras.
尽管我们要查的时间范围很小  也需要
Even though we have a very narrow time frame, it's gonna
花上几个小时才能全部看完
take a couple of hours to get through all of it.
也许我们对被告的看法是错的
Maybe we're wrong about the defendant.
也许我们应该调查一下陪审员
Maybe we should be looking at a juror.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
托尼·缪勒  4号陪审员
Tony Muller. Juror number four.
谋杀案发生后他就失踪了
He's been missing since the murder.
他没有来参加我们的问话
He was a no-show for one of our interviews.
他也不接电话  邻居们看到他
He's not answering his cell. Neighbors saw him
带着一个过夜行李离开了公寓
leave his apartment with an overnight bag.
好的  在监控录像上注意一下这个人
All right, keep an eye out for him on the video.
-我已经对他发了全面通缉  -是吗
- I already got an A.P.B.out on him. - Oh, you do?
-嗯  -干得不错
- Mm-hmm. - Good.
被害陪审员的弟弟来了
The brother of your dead juror's here.
我原以为法庭应该是很安全的
I thought courtrooms were supposed to be safe.
我很抱歉  麦丘茨克先生
I'm so sorry, Mr. McUsic.
我们正在尽全力查明真相
We're doing everything we can to figure it out.
但是谁会想要伤害乔呢
But who would want to hurt Joe? Well,
有可能和你哥哥本身没有关系
you know, it might not have to do with your brother.
或许和他所在的陪审团有关
It might have to do with the jury that he served on.
你知道他被分配到埃迪森的审判吗
Did you know that he was assigned the Addison trial?
不知道
No.
不知道  我只知道他要去做陪审员
No. I just knew he had jury duty.
你能不能想到任何你哥哥偏袒
Can you think of any reasons why your brother might have been
或者是反对被告的原因吗
biased either toward or against the defendant?
当我哥还是个孩子的时候
when he was a kid,
他做过一些违法的事
my brother had a few scrapes with the law.
但他重新做人了
But he cleaned his life up.
他坚信人应该有第二次机会
He believed in second chances.
这就是为什么他要开办过渡教习所的原因
That's why he ran the halfway house.
但他不相信什么第三  四  五次机会
What he didn't believe in were third, fourth, fifth chances.
他在外面混了很长时间
He'd been out there long enough to know,
他知道有些人就是屡教不改
some folks can't be rehabilitated.
你知道你哥哥
Do you know if your brother
在工作上和谁有矛盾吗
had any problems with anyone at work?
鉴于和他打交道的人都是...
I mean, given the kinds of people that he dealt with...
没有  乔很会与人相处
No. Joe had a way with folks.
他很关照他人
He'd look out for people.
你觉得乔是被随机选中的
You think Joe was chosen at random,
还是因为他的背景而被杀
or do you think he was killed because of his background?
事实上  由于这不是葛里逊的小说
Well, since this isn't, in fact, a Grisham novel,
我觉得我得保持一个开阔的思路
I thought I'd keep an open mind.
莱恩  能调查一下乔·麦丘茨克的过渡教习所吗
Hey, Ryan. Can you look into Joe McUsic's halfway house,
看看那里是否有人与他有矛盾
see if he had problems with anyone there?
我已经和那里的员工谈过了
I already spoke with staff.
他们不记得发生过冲突
They don't remember any conflicts,
但为了以防万一
but they're sending over a
他们给我发来了一份常驻人员名单
list of residents in case.
我们那位失踪的陪审员
Yo. Our missing juror?
州警在乔治·华盛顿大桥上发现了他
Troopers picked him up crossing the G.W. Bridge.
他们正把他带到局里来
They're bringing him in now.
你出城出得很仓促啊  缪勒先生
You were leaving town in a hurry, Mr. Muller.
-有什么原因吗  -这不明摆的事吗
- Any reason why? - Isn't it obvious?
我死定了  老兄
I'm marked for death, man.
死定了
Marked for death?
我并没有要求当陪审员  我是被传唤的
I didn't ask for jury duty. I was summoned.
他们说要我在此时此地出现
They said show up at this time at this place.
但他们没告诉我被告的哥们儿
They failed to mention that the defendant's homeboy
-会来杀我  -被告的哥们儿
- was gonna kill me. - The defendant's homeboy?
没错  是个又壮又凶的黑人
Yeah. This big scary black guy.
到底发生了什么  缪勒先生
Exactly what happened, Mr. Muller?
昨天  这家伙尾随我到法庭的厕所里
Yesterday, this guy follows me into the courthouse bathroom
然后开始和我聊关于审判的事
and starts chatting me up about the trial.
-他告诉你他叫什么了吗  -没有
- Did he give you his name? - No, no.
但他一直不停地说奥蒂斯·威廉斯是清白的
But he's going on and on about how Otis Williams is innocent
他是如何被司法体系所陷害的
and how he's being railroaded by the system.
结果今早  我在被告的
And then this morning, I see the same guy
旁听席前排看到了他
on the defendant's side of the gallery
他在盯着我看
in the front row, eyeballing me.
你以前看过他和乔在一起吗
Have you ever seen him with Joe?
见过  所以当我看到乔在我眼前
Yes, which is why when I saw Joe bite it
挂掉时  我知道我就是下一个
right in front of me, I knew I was next.
干嘛要我去死
And why should I die?
我只不过在努力履行我的公民义务罢了
I was only trying to fulfill my civic responsibilities.
谢谢你来这一趟  缪勒先生
Thank you for coming in, Mr. Muller.
你认为你能把他的长相
Now do you think you'll be able to describe him
描述给我们的速描师吗
to our sketch artist?
他是个又壮又凶的黑人
He--he's a big scary black guy.
如果你能说得再具体点就会有所帮助
It might help if you're just a little more specific.
好吧
Uh, okay. Uh...
就像我所说的  他是...
Well, like I said, he's a--
他是个又壮又凶的黑人
he's a big scary black guy
名叫沃德尔·威廉斯
named Wardell Williams.
是被告的堂弟
The defendant's cousin.
我...我以为你不知道他是谁
I didn't--I thought you didn't know who he was.
我是不知道  不过他不就在那儿吗
I didn't, but there he is.
-你确定吗  -当然
- Well, a-are you sure? - Yeah.
为什么这么问
Why?
你们在审讯缪勒先生的时候
While you guys were in the box with Mr. Muller,
我在法庭的监控录像上发现了这个
I-I found this on courthouse surveillance.
看  那是陪审员乔在咖啡机旁
See, that's Joe the juror at the coffee machine
大约在他死前14分钟  正好在谋杀时间区内
roughly 14 minutes before his death, right in our kill zone.
-是堂弟沃德尔  -再看这个
- Cousin Wardell. - And watch this.
看上去他给乔了一杯死亡咖啡
Looks like he makes a killer cup of Joe.
玩笑开得太早了吗
Too soon?
翻译：咖啡十三   cam小池   深深   落末一地   LyraL   思无邪   irene430
时间轴：小穗   好油油    校对：大卫熊   后期&总监：瓜瓜
你们就想用这种粗制滥造的
Now y'all trying to accuse me of murder
泽普鲁德电影来指控我犯了谋杀罪吗
with this half-assed version of a Zapruder film?
你和奥蒂斯不仅仅是堂兄弟的关系
You and Otis were more than just cousins.
在同一家庭里长大
Grew up in the same household.
更像是亲兄弟
More like brothers.
没错  我和奥蒂斯关系很铁  那又怎样
Yeah, me and O. tight. So what?
这就说明你会为他做一切事情
So it makes sense you'd do anything him,
包括杀死一位审判他谋杀案的陪审员
including kill a juror on his murder trial.
老兄  你们太扯了
Man, y'all reaching.
是吗
Are we?
你和陪审员交谈过  那可是操纵陪审团
You talked to jurors. That's jury tampering.
就是说起诉一个并没有犯罪的黑人
So accusing one black man of a murder he didn't commit
对你们来说还不满足  你们在尝试双赌法吗
isn't good enough for you? Y'all trying for the daily double?
我和那个法庭里面的很多人都聊过天
Man, I talked to a gang of folks in that courthouse.
我怎么会知道他们中哪个人是陪审员
How I'm supposed to know which one of them is a juror?
他们衣服上"陪审员"的徽章
Well, the "Juror" badges on their shirts
-也许是个不错的提示  -通过监控视频的镜头
- might have been a hint. - Using video surveillance footage
鉴证组成功地从垃圾箱中找到了乔的咖啡杯
C.S.U. managed to pull joe's coffee cup out of the garbage.
他们在检测是否含有氰化物
They're testing it for cyanide.
你为何不在我们还能谈条件时
Why don't you just come clean
交待事实呢
while we still got a deal to make?
我跟你说过了  我什么也没做
Man, I told you, I didn't do nothin'!
沃德尔  坐下  别逼我动粗
Wardell, sit down before I make you sit down.
很显然  你是那个唱白脸的警察
So obviously, you must be the bad cop.
这样你就是唱红脸的咯
Guess that makes you the good cop.
实际上  我不是警察
Actually, I'm not a cop.
-你不是警察啊  -卡塞尔先生是位作家
- Oh, you not a cop? - Mr. Castle is a writer.
他时不时协助警局办案
He consults with the department on occasion.
你们是这个套路啊
Oh. So that's how you two do it?
你说假话  你写假话
You tell the lies, you print the lies?
你们就像他们陷害我堂哥那样来陷害我
Man, y'all framing me just like they did my cousin.
那整件事完全是个阴谋
That whole damn thing a conspiracy.
沃德尔  认真点
Wardell, be serious.
你觉得我不是认真的吗
You don't think I'm serious?
那告诉我  城里这么多律师
Then tell me, why of all the lawyers in the city,
为什么是地检官接手了奥蒂斯的案子
the district attorney is trying Otis' case?
你不认为这是因为他在竞选市长
You don't think it's 'cause he's running for mayor
他想通过把我堂哥关起来
and he wants to lock my cousin up
让他那些有钱有权的白人朋友感觉安全吗
so all his rich, powerful white friends can feel safe?
你这么做完全不能帮助你自己
Look, you're not doing yourself any favors right now.
你们把一切都设计好了
You just got it all worked out, huh?
你们把我堂哥奥蒂斯塑造成比格·托马斯
You got my cousin O. pulling a Bigger Thomas.
然后你们又指控我杀了这个男人来使他脱罪
And you got me poisoning this man to get him off.
看起来是这样的
Looks that way.
"看起来"并不代表那是真相
Well, looks don't make it so.
看上去我在给这个男人的咖啡下毒
Looks like I'm poisoning this man's coffee...
其实  我所做的不过是把咖啡递给他
when really, all I did was hand it to him.
-埃斯波西托  -嗯
-Hey, esposito. - Hmm?
去申请沃德尔住所的搜查令
Can you get a warrant for Wardell's place,
-看有没有氰化物残留  -马上去
- see if there's any traces of cyanide? - You got it.
正如法律术语中说的  真相大白了
And as they say in legalese, asked and answered.
真可惜  我本以为这件事
It's too bad. I was hoping there'd be a little more
会牵扯出更多内幕的
to the story than that.
哼
Hmm.
你那声"哼"什么意思
"Hmm," what?
阿丽克西斯说她今天去格林威治村
Alexis said she'd be in the village today,
但她其实在威廉斯堡
but she's over in Williamsburg.
你怎么知道她在威廉斯堡
Well, how do you know she's in Williamsburg?
用卫星定位她手机
GPS tracked her phone.
你追踪了她手机吗
You tracked her phone?
是啊  我刚才下载的一个超酷软件
Yeah. Super cool app I just downloaded.
我能随时掌握她的行踪
I can see where she is at anytime.
她知道你这么做吗
Does she know that you're doing this?
你在开玩笑吗  她会杀了我的
What, are you kidding? No, she'd kill me.
杀你也是你活该
And be justified.
我是她老爸
I'm her father.
要是有什么事  我得知道
If something's going on, I-I need to know.
很多家长
A lot of parents
都喜欢翻孩子的抽屉或是电脑
will go through their kids' drawers or computers.
这方法温和多了
Far less intrusive.
这是乔掺了氰化物的咖啡杯
Joe's cyanide-laced coffee cup.
鉴证组在上面发现乔和沃德尔的指纹
C.S.U. found both Joe and Wardell's prints on it,
但少了样重要的东西
but there was something very important missing.
氰化物
Cyanide.
-真的  -真的
- Really? - Really.
那他怎么被下毒的
Well, how was he poisoned?
解剖时我在处方缓释胶囊内
During the autopsy, I discovered cyanide residue
发现了氰化物残留物
in a prescription time-release capsule.
乔开了氰化物处方药吗
So Joe had a prescription for cyanide?
不  他的处方药是皮质激素
No. He had a prescription for corticosteroids.
他的内科医生说  他每天早上服一粒
According to his physician, he took one every morning
治疗狼疮
for symptoms from lupus.
看来有人调换了
It looks like the killer
乔的胶囊内含物
switched out the contents of Joe's capsule
放入了氰化物
and replaced it with the cyanide.
就是说乔服药的时候
Okay, so then when Joe was taking his medications,
-不知不觉就给自己下毒了  -不过还有个问题
- he unknowingly poisoned himself. - But here's the rub--
因为放入氰化物的缓释胶囊
since the cyanide was in a time-release capsule
并不是设计成溶解于胃里的
designed not to dissolve in stomach acid,
-而是溶解于肠里  -咱们的时间顺序全乱了
- but in the intestines... - Our timeline is all screwed up.
没错  实际上乔
Yep, turns out Joe
是在死前一小时左右被下毒的
was poisoned almost one hour before his death
也就是8点13分
at 8:13 this morning.
那时他都还没抵达法院
That's before he even got to the courthouse.
说明凶手可能也不在那里
Which means the killer probably wasn't there either.
就是说乔的死或许跟这场审判根本没关系
Then Joe's death might not have anything to do with the trial.
我们得知了三个重要线索
Well, we learned three very important things.
第一  凶手足够恶毒
Firstly, our killer is diabolical.
居然能让人稀里糊涂的自杀
You let someone unwittingly kill themselves?
太邪恶了
Pure evil.
第二  凶手了解乔  至少了解他的习惯
Second, our killer knew joe or at least knew his habits.
-第三  凶手是女人  -啊
- Third, our killer was a woman. - Hmm?
从统计学角度看  下毒这种手段
Statistically speaking, poisonings are almost always
-女人才会用  -但你遗漏了
- carried out by the fairer sex. - Ah, but you are missing
-一个非常重要的细节  卡塞尔  -点醒我
- one very important detail, Castle. - Enlighten me.
凶手能接触到乔的药物
Our killer had access to Joe's medications,
这些药物他根本不带在自己身上
medications that he did not keep on him.
-就是说凶手能接触到他的...  -他的住处
- So therefore our killer had access to... - his apartment.
没错
Bingo.
纽约警察
NYPD.
我说  陪审员乔之死
You know, the murder of Joe the juror
真是一场悲剧
is a real tragedy.
每宗谋杀不都是悲剧吗
Isn't every murder a tragedy?
对  每宗谋杀都是悲剧  但乔很特别
Yes, every murder's a tragedy, but Joe is special.
他曾是少年犯  他改过自新
He was a juvenile delinquent who reformed himself,
重新做人
a born-again citizen
他信任法制  帮助有前科的人
who believed in the system and helped out ex-cons.
而他大费周章得到了什么呢
And what did he get for his trouble?
一粒满是毒药的胶囊
Hmm. Pill full of poison.
"懦夫在未死以前  就已经死过好多次
"Cowards die many times before their death.
勇士一生只死一次"
The valiant never taste of death but once."
老兄  你可不是卡塞尔
Bro, you're not Castle.
我知道我不是卡塞尔
Yeah, I know I'm not Castle.
那就别再学他讲话
Then stop trying to talk like him.
难道我就不能引用一下诗人的言语吗
What, I'm not allowed to reference the bard?
我可是很多才多艺的
I'm a renaissance man.
背一句名言可算不上是多才多艺
Memorizing one quote does not make you a renaissance man.
那我背两句呢
What if I memorized two?
你背够两句了吗
Have you memorized two?
还没  要是我能呢
No, but what if I did?
那就看你背什么了
Depends on the quote.
你这家伙是谁
Now who the hell are you?
汉克·庞泽尔
Hank Ponzell,
乔·麦丘茨克过渡教习所的前任常驻人员
former resident of Joe McUsic's halfway house,
直到乔拒绝了你的延期并把你赶出去
until you were kicked out when Joe denied your extension.
-你肯定很恼火  汉克  -你们不明白
- That had to make you mad, huh, Hank? - You don't understand.
不  我们明白  乔把你逼得走投无路
Oh, no. I think we do. Joe kicked you to the curb,
于是你就给他下毒
and you poisoned him.
实验室测试结果表明每一个胶囊里
Lab report shows that every one of these capsules
-都有氰化物  -要是我给他下毒
- tested positive for cyanide. - If I poisoned him,
我还待在他公寓里干什么
why would I still be in his apartment?
把剩下的胶囊拿走
To take the rest of the poisoned pills away
让我们找不到  就能掩盖你的踪迹
so we couldn't find them, so you could hide your tracks.
我整天都不在屋里
I was out of the apartment all day.
任何人都可能进去  何况我不会伤害乔的
Anyone could've gotten in there. And I would never hurt Joe.
他是我朋友
He was my friend.
-就这朋友  -就是
- Friends like him, huh? - Right?
我没给他下毒  乔让我待在那里的
I didn't poison him. Joe was letting me stay there, okay?
我在过渡教习所驻留时间到了上限
I maxed out my time at the halfway house
可我没有地方去
and didn't have a place to go.
乔破例让我跟他暂住
Joe broke the rules and let me crash with him.
那你干嘛在他衣橱里玩捉迷藏
Then why were you playing hide-and-go-seek in his closet?
我是假释期的重犯
I'm a felon on parole.
我听到警察来  当罪犯当习惯了  就躲了起来
I hear cops, and my ex-con instincts kick in.
好吧  如果你是在改造自己
Okay, if you were there on the up-and-up,
那告诉我们  乔有什么麻烦吗
tell us, was Joe in any kind of trouble?
听着老兄
Look, buddy,
我觉得你没太弄明白你的处境
I don't think you appreciate the situation you're in.
你还在假释期
You are on parole,
却卷入谋杀案调查之中
and you're up to your neck in a homicide investigation.
你最好老实交代  不然我们会在
Now you better start talking, or we're gonna have you
纽约新新监狱晚上点名前把你送回去
back in Sing Sing before the evening roll call.
好吧  乔让我帮他跑腿
All right. Joe had me run errands for him, okay?
取干洗的衣服  去趟酒窖什么的
Pick up laundry, go to the bodega, stuff like that.
几个周前  他给了我个信封
A few weeks ago, he gave me an envelope
-让我带给一位女士  -信封里是什么
- and told me to take it to this lady. - What was in the envelope?
现金  大概有两千美金
Cash. Like 2 grand.
但我发誓不知道那是要做什么
But I don't know what it was for. I swear.
乔总是在谈论他如何脱离了犯罪生涯
Joe always talked about how he got out of the criminal life,
但或许他还没金盆洗手
but maybe he still had a foot in.
你把那个信封给了哪位女士
Who was this lady that you delivered the envelope to?
詹金斯女士
Ms. Jenkins?
我是
Yes.
你是不是住在西端大道3751号
Do you live at 3751 West End Ave.?
-是  -我们得谈谈
- Yes. - We need to chat.
是我做的  是我做的  是我做的
I did it. I did it. I did it.
你杀了他
You killed him?
我的天  当然没有
Oh, my god, no. Of course not.
你怎么会这么想
Why would you think that?
因为你刚才说"是我做的"
Because you just said "I did it."
不不不  不是谋杀  天啊
Oh, no, no, not murder. No, god.
我做了别的  很...糟糕的事
I-I did something else. Something... awful.
詹金斯女士  你是法庭书记员
Ms. Jenkins, you're the court clerk.
乔·麦丘茨克为什么会给你那么多钱
Why did Joe McUsic give you that much money?
他付钱让我送他上陪审席
He paid me to put him on that jury.
乔·麦丘茨克找到我
Joe McUsic came to me
说他想履行陪审职责
and said he wanted to serve his jury duty.
我没觉得有什么问题
I didn't see the harm.
当然了  尤其你还能小赚一笔
Sure. I mean, especially if you're gonna make a profit.
我的室友两个月前搬走了
My roommate moved out two months ago.
我需要钱付房租  我就想
I needed the extra cash for rent, and I figured,
神不知鬼不觉嘛  不过是陪审职责
who's gonna know? I mean, it's jury duty.
拜托了  千万不要送我去监狱
Please, please, don't send me to prison.
我一天到晚  见识过被送往监狱的女人什么样
All day long, I-I see the women who get sent there,
我应付不了
and... I can't hack it.
早餐前我就会变成某个终身囚犯的"婊子"的
I'll be some lifer's bitch before breakfast.
乔是专门要求
Okay, Joe specifically asked
参加奥蒂斯·威廉斯的庭审的吗
to be on Otis Williams' trial?
是的  他打定主意要进入那次审判的陪审池
Yes. He was insistent about getting on that jury pool.
他说了原因吗
Did he tell you why?
没有  不过那可是莱拉·埃迪森一案
No, but it was the Lyla Addison case,
我就猜测他是想写一本
so I figured maybe he wanted to write
揭露案件的书之类的
a tell-all book about it or something.
我发誓  我只是把他弄进陪审池
I-I swear, all I did was put him in the pool.
他是自己通过陪审团挑选的
He got through jury selection on his own.
莱恩和埃斯波西托查看了乔的电脑
Ryan and Esposito looked at Joe's computer.
里面没有任何他在写有关案件的书
There's no evidence that he was writing a book
或记录案件的迹象
or even taking notes on the trial.
一个陪审员把自己买进了陪审团却遭谋杀
So a murdered juror just bought himself on to the jury,
而我们还一点头绪都没有
and we still have no idea why?
凶杀  谜案
A murder, a mystery,
融合了法庭惊悚情节
wrapped up inside a courtroom thriller--
约翰·葛里逊竟然没写这本书
I can't believe John Grisham hasn't written this book.
我倒希望他写了  我们或许就能知道
I wish he had, maybe then we'd know
那案子对乔有何特殊之处了
what was so special about that trial to Joe.
可能乔和这件案子有点个人联系
Well, maybe Joe had a personal connection to the trial--
比如和被害人莱拉·埃迪森
to the victim, Lyla Addison,
或和被告奥蒂斯·威廉斯
or to the defendant, Otis Williams.
乔有少年犯罪记录吗
Doesn't Joe have a juvie record?
-有  -要是他以前就认识奥蒂斯呢
- Mm-hmm.  - What if he knew Otis from back in the day?
他们可能一起被抓过
They could've gotten arrested together
或同在一所青少年拘留所待过
or maybe spent some time in the same juvenile hall.
很有可能  我查一下
That's a good idea. I'll look into it.
还有  我会让人把莱拉·埃迪森一案的
Meanwhile, I'll have Lyla Addison's case file
资料送过来
sent over from the 7-4,
你们最好找她的家人再了解一下
and you should check in with the family.
可能会有所发现
Could be a connection there.
-好的  -晚安  卡塞尔
- Okay.  - Good night, Castle.
晚安
Night.
嘿  老爸  在写作啊
Hey, dad. Writing?
是啊  今天玩的怎样
Yeah. How was your day?
在格林威治村玩的开心吗
Did you have a good time in the village?
-开心  -还去别处玩了吗
- Yeah.  - Go anywhere else?
呃  没有  就在格林威治村
Uh, no. Just stayed in the village.
是吗
Really?
我是说  纽约是个大城市
I mean, New York is a big city.
有很多个区呢
Lots of boroughs.
是啊  但我就在曼哈顿区玩
Yeah, but I just stayed in Manhattan.
你没去  布鲁克林区吗
So you didn't go to, uh... Brooklyn?
这时候的威廉斯堡很漂亮
Williamsburg is beautiful this time of year.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我朋友告诉我的  他去了那儿  看到了你
A friend of mine told me. He went there. He saw you.
哪个朋友
What friend?
很好的朋友  JJ·亚当斯
A close friend. J.J... Adams.
抽动鼻子  露馅了  你在撒谎
Nose twitch. That's your tell. You're lying.
-不  我没撒谎  -那JJ·亚当斯是谁
- No, I'm not.  - Then who is J.J. Adams?
他是我一个朋友
He's a friend of mine.
等等  JJ·亚当斯是莱斯利·尼尔森
Wait. J.J. Adams was Leslie Nielsen's character name
在《禁忌星球》里所饰演的角色  你绝对是撒谎
in "Forbidden planet." You're totally lying.
你怎么知道我在那里  你找人跟踪我
How did you know where I was? Are you having me followed?
监控我的地铁卡  还是查我的信用卡
Monitoring my metro card? Checking my credit...
手机
My phone.
爸爸  告诉我你没有追踪我的手机
Dad, tell me you are not tracking my phone.
听我说  我做了什么不重要
Okay, look, this is not about what I did.
重要的是你做了什么  你骗了我
It's about what you did. You lied to me.
侵犯自己女儿民事权利的人  还好意思说这个
Says the man who violated his daughter's civil rights.
等等  严格来说  我是政府部门的话
Okay, technically, I would have to be the government
-才算是侵犯  -你在监视我的一举一动
- to violate--  - You're tracking my every move.
不是一举一动
Not your every move.
欢迎来到乔治·奥威尔的《1984》
Welcome to George Orwell's "1984,"
-由我父亲扮演大老哥  -这不是
- with my father as Big Brother.  - This isn't about--
下一步要怎样  在我脑子里放芯片吗
What's next, a chip in my brain?
你要是对我有所隐瞒  我会想尽办法知道的
Whatever it takes when you're keeping secrets from me.
我告诉你  既然你对我的事这么感兴趣
You know what? If you're so interested in what I'm doing,
何不问你的手机呢
why don't you ask your phone?
肯定有这方面的软件
I'm sure there's an app for that.
卡塞尔  你这是自食其果
You had it coming, Castle.
你有世界上最乖巧的孩子
I mean, you have the best kid in the world,
却把她当犯人一样对待
and you treated her like a common criminal.
可能她就是呢
Maybe she is, though.
我还是不明白她为什么撒谎
I still don't know why she lied about
说没去威廉斯堡
going to williamsburg.
你可能永远也不会知道了
And you probably never will,
除非你打算对她施用水刑
unless you plan on waterboarding her.
说实话  我做的真的很过分吗
Honestly, is what I did so wrong?
我觉得那对阿丽克西斯来说不重要
I don't really think that it matters to Alexis.
重要的是你打破了她对你的信任
I mean, you broke her trust.
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
那我现在该怎么办
So what do I do now?
把它赢回来
Win it back.
走吧  莱拉的家人在等着呢
Come on. Lyla's family's waiting.
没有  除了在陪审员席我没见过他
No, I've never seen him outside the jury box.
其他人也没见过
Don't think any of us have.
一个陪审员为了进入陪审团而行贿
Well, a juror bribing his way onto a trial?
在我25年的检察官生涯中
I've never in my 25 years as a prosecutor
-还从未遇到这类情况  -埃迪森先生
- seen anything like it.  - Mr. Addison,
有没有可能你女儿认识这个人
Is it at all possible that your daughter knew this man?
不可能
No.
史蒂芬
Stephen?
我妹妹大部分的朋友我都认识
I know most of my sister's friends.
他不在其中
He's not one of 'em.
如果是她的朋友的话  他为什么要这么做呢
And if he was, why would he have done this?
他为什么要让我妹妹的公正受到威胁呢
Why would he put my sister's shot at justice in jeopardy?
罗伊  我想不必我多说
Roy, I don't think I need to tell you
你知道这对城市的法制系统会造成多大的危害
how catastrophic this could be to the city's legal system.
我希望乔·麦丘茨克谋杀案尽快解决
Now I need Joe McUsic's murder solved.
-情况有多糟  路  -非常糟
- How bad are things, Lou?  - It's pretty bad.
今天早上在预先审查时  有陪审团候补人员
Just this morning at voir dire, I had potential jurors
对自己的人身安全表示担忧
expressing fears for their own personal safety.
现在纽约市民需要确保
Now the people of New York need to be assured
他们是受到保护的
that they are protected.
及时通知我案情进展
Keep me in the loop.
我指挥12分局这么多年
In all the years I've been in command of the 12th precinct,
你们知道地检官来过多少次吗
you know how many times the district attorney has shown up?
一次  就在今天
Once. Today.
-你们都听到了  赶紧做事  -是  长官
- You heard the man. Let's get to work.  - Yes, sir.
乔和莱拉·埃迪森之间没有任何联系
There is no Joe connection to Lyla Addison.
没有财务往来
There's nothing in her financials,
案件档案上没有记载  没有邮件往来
her murder file, her e-mails,
没有短信往来  甚至年鉴上都没提到过
her texts, not even her yearbook.
乔和莱拉绝对没有任何交集
Joe and Lyla have absolutely nothing in common.
他们两个似乎
It's like the two of them didn't even
-生活在两个不同的星球  -乔和奥蒂斯也是
- live on the same planet.  - Same goes with Joe and Otis.
少年犯罪档案里也没任何线索
There's no Joe conction in the juvie files?
没有  都不沾边
No, not even close.
乔和奥蒂斯在不同时间被送往不同的
Joe and Otis were sent to different juvie halls
拘留所  而且相距十万八千里
at different times, and they ran in opposite neighborhoods.
那他到底为什么这么想进陪审团呢
So then why the hell did he want to get on that jury so bad?
等等  我这里有发现
Wait a minute I think I got something.
找到联系了吗
You have a connection?
根据他的信用卡消费记录  两个月前
According to his credit card, Joe purchased
乔在一家电子商店购买了一支
a pay-as-you-go cell phone from an electronics store
付费使用的手机
a couple of months back.
-然后呢  -他本来就有手机
-So?  - So he already had a cell phone.
还买这么个一次性手机干什么呢
What's he need a burner phone for,
而且还是匿名的
especially an anonymous one?
若他在用的话  手机在哪里呢
And if he is using it, where is it?
好  带一队人去他公寓
All right, take a crew to his apartment,
看有没有什么线索
see what you can find.
-那可能就是我们要找的突破口  -是的
- That might be the break that we need.  - Yeah.
卡塞尔  卡塞尔  你能别玩了吗
Castle? Castle, can you stop playing around?
事实上  我不是在玩
Actually, I'm not playing around.
我在忙着拨开这件案子的迷雾呢
I'm a little busy blowing this case wide open.
这是一张案发现场的
This is a photograph of the looky loos
围观群众的照片
at Lyla's crime scene.
这是个放大软件
This is a little magnification app.
认出谁来了吗
Recognize anyone?
是乔
It's Joe.
他在莱拉·埃迪森一案的案发现场
He was at Lyla Addison's crime scene.
他为什么会在那里
Why would he be there?
一个公民会出现在凶杀现场
Only three reasons for a civilian
只有三个原因  一是他们死了
to be at a murder scene-- one, they're dead,
二是他们碰巧出现在这个区域
two, they just happen to be in the immediate area,
还有三  就是凶手压抑不住
or three, it's our killer, and he couldn't resist
返回犯罪现场的冲动
the compulsion to return to the scene of the crime.
你们觉得乔是属于哪个类型的
And which number do you think Joe is?
我选第三种
I'm gonna go with three.
他既是被害人又是凶手
He's our victim and our killer.
厉害
Nice.
-疼  -对不起
- Ah. - Sorry.
乔·麦丘茨克  既是被害人也是凶手
Joe McUsic -- victim and killer?
这真是最棒的反转
This is the best twist yet.
乔在自己犯下的谋杀案审判中担当陪审员
Joe served on the jury of a murder he committed.
是啊  但如果乔逃脱了谋杀的罪名
Yeah, but if Joe literally got away with murder,
他为什么还要冒这么大的险
why would he risk it all
通过贿赂的方式成为陪审员呢
and bribe his way onto the jury?
也许他觉得有义务去救一个清白的人
Maybe he felt compelled to save an innocent man.
也许他想制造
Maybe he wanted to create reasonable doubt
一个合理疑点让奥蒂斯脱罪
in the deliberation room to get Otis off,
就像亨利·方达在《十二怒汉》中的手法一样
just like Henry Fonda in "12 Angry Men."
又或者他混进陪审团是想确保
Or maybe he got onto the jury because he wanted to make sure
清白的奥蒂斯被定罪
that an innocent Otis got convicted of his crime.
不  我还是喜欢"有良心的杀手"这一推理
No. I like my "killer with a conscience" theory better.
是吗  好吧  随你怎么喜欢你的推理
Yeah? Well, like your theory all you want.
我的推理没有那么复杂做作
Mine is less convoluted and contrived.
我不想煞风景  但你们都错了
I hate to burst bubbles, but you're both wrong.
莱拉不是乔杀的
Joe did not kill Lyla.
他有不在场证明
He had an alibi.
我对过渡教习所进行了调查
I did a background on the halfway house.
在莱拉被杀的当晚
On the night Lyla was killed,
乔在筹款
Joe was at a fund-raiser.
他一直在那待到午夜
He was there until midnight.
莱拉是在晚上9:30到11:30之间被杀的
And Lyla was killed between 9:30 and 11:30 p.m.
那既然不是他杀的人
So if he didn't kill her,
他为什么那么想进陪审团呢
why did he want to be on the jury so bad?
他又为什么会出现在凶案现场
And why was he at the crime scene?
好吧  现在我们知道
Okay, so we know
乔做陪审员有不可告人的目的
that Joe was a juror with a hidden agenda.
他被卷入了这场高调的案子
He was embroiled in a high-profile case
地方检察官亲自接手此案
being tried by the D.A. himself.
但他还没能完成他预谋之事
But before he could accomplish what he set out to do,
就被暗中的强大势力灭了口
he was struck down by powerful, shadowy forces.
有什么发现
What?
我们一定遗漏了某些线索
There's gotta be something that we're missing.
乔和被告之间一定有
There has to be a tangible connection
某些实际的关联
between Joe and our defendant
或者是乔和被害人之间有联系
or Joe and our victim.
又或者是乔和其他人之间有联系
Or between Joe and somebody else entirely.
我找到一个手机
I found a phone.
藏在书柜的书后面
It was hiding behind some books in the bookcase.
乔用它打了十四通电话
Joe made 14 calls with it,
全打给了一个号码
all to the same number.
地方检察官路·卡耐基的办公室
District Attorney Lou Karnacki's office.
看来地方检察官违反规程了
Looks like the D.A. was out of order.
-克雷格太太  -请叫我唐
- Mrs. Craig. - Oh, please. Call me Dawn.
唐  你是
Dawn, you are
我们这的地方检察官的行政助理吧
our district attorney's administrative assistant?
是的  从他来这以后一直是我
Yes, ever since he came into office.
你印象中有没有收到过
Do you remember ever receiving
一个叫乔·麦丘茨克的人打来的电话
any phone calls from a Joe McUsic?
我们每天都要接成百上千个电话
Ooh. Uh, we get hundreds of calls every day.
好像没听过这么个人
Um, that name doesn't sound familiar.
我们有充分的理由证明他打来过很多次
We have reason to believe he called numerous times.
他也许说过
He may have said
是关于奥蒂斯·威廉斯的案子的
it was regarding the Otis Williams case.
有的
Oh. Uh, yeah.
我是接到过一些奇怪的匿名电话
I did get a series of bizarre anonymous calls
那个男人声称奥蒂斯·威廉斯是无辜的
from a man claiming that Otis Williams was innocent.
那人可能就是乔
That would be Joe.
他有跟地检官通过话吗
Did he ever speak to the D.A.?
没有  我从没把这些电话转接给他
No. I never put him through.
我觉得那人就是个疯子
I figured he was a wacko.
我们经常接到类似的电话
Well, you know, we get a lot of these calls,
我一半的工作就是把
and half my job is to filter out
正常的电话从这些疯子电话中过滤出来
the legitimate calls from the crackpots.
那他有没有提过别的什么事
Did he ever mention anything else?
有  他说过他有能让
Yeah. He said he had evidence
奥蒂斯·威廉斯脱罪的证据
that would exonerate Otis Williams,
还有他打算把证据寄到
and how he was gonna mail it
地方检察官的办公室
to the District Attorney's office.
你收到这个包裹了吗
Did you ever get that package?
据我了解没有
Not that I know of.
唐  这些电话时长基本上
Uh, Dawn, most of these phone calls
都不到两分钟
are under two minutes long.
但是这有一通晚上10:14打的
But then there's this one at 10:14 p.m.
都超过十分钟了
It's over ten minutes long.
有没有可能是你接到的这个电话呢
Is there any chance that you took that phone call?
不可能  我从来不会待到七点以后
Oh, no. I never stay past 7:00.
地方检察官一般工作到几点
How late does the D.A. work?
谈话结束了
This conversation is over.
你就这么通知我进展的吗  罗伊
This the way you keep me in the loop, Roy?
路  这案子进展很快
It's a fast-moving case, Lou.
我的手下只是跟着证据走
My team just followed the evidence where it led them.
别用这个搪塞我
Oh, don't give me that.
我们认识这么久了
We've known each other too long.
卡耐基先生  乔·麦丘茨克往您办公室
Mr. Karnacki, Joe McUsic made several phone calls
打了好几通电话
to your office.
其中有一通通话超过了十分钟
One of them lasted over ten minutes.
您跟他说话了吗  长官
Did you speak to him, sir?
那个死了的陪审员
The dead juror?
-是的  -没有  当然没有
- Yes. - No, of course not.
他有没有给你寄过一些
Did he send you any evidence
与奥蒂斯·威廉斯的案子相关的证据
that was relevant to the Otis Williams case?
抱歉  我想我们还没有正式介绍
Excuse me. I don't think we've been introduced.
我是那个可以禁止你出入这个分局的人
I'm the guy that can get you banned from this precinct.
我也可以把你调到港口分局
And I can have you transferred to the harbor unit!
路  你说过要尽快查出真凶
Lou, you said you wanted this murder squared away.
我们现在就是这么做的
That's all we're doing.
不  你们这是在我背后鬼鬼祟祟
No, what you're doing is sneaking around behind my back.
下次你如果想问话  打电话
Now the next time you want an interview, you call.
不要再背着我  把我的任何一个员工
And don't you ever, ever, drag one of my staff down here
拖到这里来
without my knowledge again.
你没通知地检官
You called in the D.A.'s personal assistant
就把他的个人助理叫到这问话了吗
without informing him?
对不起  长官  我
Sir, I'm sorry. I was...I...
这招聪明
Smart move.
没看到刚刚发生的事吗
Don't you see what just happened?
他本可以打电话询问为什么他的助理在这
He could have called and asked why his assistant was here,
但是他却亲自过来了
but he came in person.
他想终止这次问话
He wanted to stop the interview.
他在掩盖线索
He's hiding something.
沃德尔·威廉斯是对的  这是场阴谋
Wardell Williams was right. It's a conspiracy.
我同意
I agree.
我知道  很怪
I know. Weird.
是很怪  但是很好
Yeah, weird, but good,
因为那只是冰山一角
because that's just the tip of the iceberg.
你准备好"巨轮沉没"了吗
Are you ready for the "Titanic"?
是的
Yes.
很好  我在网上挖到了一些料
Good. I did a little digging on the internet.
猜猜地方检察官最近竞选的
Guess who the D.A.'s largest campaign contributors were
最大赞助商是谁
on his last election?
谁
Who?
鲁道夫和安德亚·埃迪森
Randolph and Andrea Addison,
是莱拉的父母
Lyla's parents.
我的推测是
Here's what I'm thinking,
悲痛欲绝的父母要声张正义
devastated parents demand justice.
坚持让地检官亲自接手这个案子
Insist that the D.A. try the case personally,
也许还暗示卡耐基
maybe even suggest to Karnacki
想要确保得到他们政治上的支持
that he needs to put Lyla's killer away
就得把杀死莱拉的凶手定罪
in order to secure their political support.
当然  卡耐基同意了
Of course, and Karnacki agreed
因为这本是一起简单的案子
because it was gonna be an easy case.
因为他们有了奥蒂斯·威廉斯这个嫌疑人
I mean, they already had Otis Williams.
定罪毫无悬念
It was open and shut.
直到乔开始打电话
Until Joe starts calling,
坚持称奥蒂斯是无辜的
insisting that Otis is innocent,
这对卡耐基很不利
which is bad for Karnacki...
实际上  最后是对乔不利
Actually, in the end, bad for Joe.
但是这还是没有解释通
You know, but it still doesn't explain
为什么乔要靠贿赂进陪审团
why Joe bought into the jury pool
或者他凭什么认为奥蒂斯·威廉斯就是无辜的
or why he thought that Otis Williams was innocent.
我是说  如果他有脱罪的证据的话  证据在哪
I mean, if he had exonerating evidence, where is it?
我们能找的地方都找了
We've looked everywhere.
能谈的人也都谈了
We've talked to everyone.
还有漏网之鱼
Not everyone.
正如我之前所说
As I said before,
我们来这不是讨论莱拉·埃迪森的案子的
we're not here to discuss the Lyla Addison case.
我们也不是
Neither are we.
我们是想谈谈乔·麦丘茨克的谋杀案
We're here to talk about Joe McUsic's murder--
7号陪审员
Juror number seven.
你们不是还在纠结
You're not still suggesting
我的当事人跟这个案子也有关系吧
that my client had something to do with that?
我们比较倾向于威廉斯先生
Uh, we are open to the idea that Mr. Williams
跟任何一个案子都没有关系
may not be guilty of either murder.
如果你能帮我们找出真凶
Look, we think that you might be able to help yourself
说不定能帮你自己洗脱罪名
by helping us find the real killer.
这是乔·麦丘茨克
This is Joe McUsic.
这次审判前你们曾经见过吗
Had you ever seen him before the trial?
他自称有能证明你清白的证据
He claimed to have evidence proving your innocence.
你知道可能是什么样的证据吗
Do you have any idea what that evidence might be?
我怎么知道
How am I supposed to know?
他靠贿赂进入陪审团
He bought his way onto the jury
就是为了让你被判无罪
in order to get you acquitted
并为此送了命
and then he got murdered for it.
听着  他死了我很遗憾
Well, look, I'm sorry he's dead.
我很感激他那样为我铤而走险
I appreciate a man putting himself out like that for me,
但  我真不知道怎么帮你们
but I don't know how to help y'all.
威廉斯先生  如果你没杀莱拉
Mr. Williams, if you didn't kill Lyla,
那我们就得找到真凶
then we need to figure out who did.
你是第一个到达现场的
You were first on the scene.
你如果记得任何细节
Any detail you can remember,
不管记得多模糊  都可能帮到我们
no matter how obscure, might help us.
好吧  那天很晚了
A'ight. It was late.
刚下班  往家走
Just got off my job, you know? Walking home...
就看到那辆漂亮的宝马760i
When I saw that sweet 760i,
就停在那  钥匙还插在上面
just sitting there, keys in the ignition.
我知道我该走开的
I knew I shoulda passed it by,
但我一直想开一回760
but I always wanted to drive a 760,
我就跳上车
so I jumped in.
打断一下  再详细点  看到别人了吗
I'm sorry. We need details. So did you see anyone?
-没有  -车周围有东西吗
- No. - Was there anything around the car?
有没有任何迹象表明有人在车里停留过
Yeah, anything that might suggest someone else had been there.
烟头  口香糖
Cigarette butts, uh, chewing gum...
鞋迹  高跟鞋印
Shoe prints, heel prints?
-没有那样的东西  -好吧  然后呢
- Nah, nothing like that. - Okay, um, what happened next?
我坐进去  把座椅向前调
I slid in the ride, pulled the seat up,
发动车子
hit the ignition...
等等  你说你把座椅向前调了
Wait, wait. Did you say you pulled the seat up?
-对啊  -你确定吗
- Yeah. - Are you sure?
我确定  座椅很靠后
Yeah, I'm sure. That bad boy was all the way back,
我就按侧面的按钮把它调向前
so I hit the button on the side to move it up.
莱拉不过5英尺[约1米5]高
Lyla was all of 5-foot-nothing.
座椅不会放到那么靠后
There's no reason for that seat to have been all the way back.
开车的另有其人
Somebody else was driving that car,
极有可能是凶手
most likely our killer.
那凶手要移动座椅就要按
And our killer would have to press the back button
后移钮  鉴证组查指纹了吗
in order to move it. Did C.S.U. check for prints?
方向盘和仪表盘都查了
The steering wheel and the dash.
只找到我当事人的指纹
The only prints they found were my client's,
他又在现场被抓住
so when they caught him behind the wheel,
所以我想他们大概也没细找
I don't think they put much effort into it.
莱拉的车在审判期间是没收在库的
Lyla's car is still at the impound pending the trial.
我们还能让鉴证组查查座椅控制钮的指纹
We can still have C.S.U. print the seat controls.
座椅控制按钮
A seat back button?
对一宗谋杀疑案来说这是非常棒的细节
What a great detail for a murder mystery.
找到指纹  才算棒
Only if we get a print.
是啊  不然我们只能到处找傻大个了
Yes, otherwise, we'll just be looking for tall people.
是啊
Yeah.
爸爸
Dad.
你好啊
Hey.
出了什么事吗
Everything all right?
对不起  我昨晚冲你吼
I'm sorry for yelling at you last...
不不  是我背叛了你的信任
No, no, I... I violated your trust.
我不该那样监视你
I shouldn't have spied on you.
那是不对的  我想让你看这个
That was wrong. And I want you to see this...
我要把这个软件
I am deleting that app...
永远删掉
now and forever.
好吗  没了
Okay? Gone.
对不起
So... I'm sorry.
原谅我了吗
Forgive me?
你会原谅我吗
But will you forgive me?
当然
Of course.
那  能告诉我
So... tell me
去威廉斯堡干嘛了
what happened in Williamsburg.
两天前  我们一群人去布鲁克林基娜之家
Two days ago, a bunch of us went to Keena's of Brooklyn.
是一家精品店
It's a boutique.
我朋友觉得如果我们都
And my friends thought it'd be cool
-顺点东西走会很酷  -你顺
- if we all took a couple of things. - You shop...
-你偷东西了  -没有
- you were shoplifting? - No.
我做不到  但是我朋友做了
I couldn't, but my friends did,
还说我胆小
and they said I was chicken.
所以你为了在你的朋友面前扮酷
So you went back to finish the job
-又回去做了  -没有
- to impress your friends. - No,
我去为他们偷走的东西付了钱
I went back to pay for what they stole.
我不能就看着有人那样被坑
I couldn't just let someone get cheated like that.
我从自己的小金库里拿了钱  回到店里
I took money out of my savings and went back to the store...
到了那  把钱和一张字条放在收银台
when I got there, I put cash on the counter with a note
然后以最快的速度跑掉了
and ran out as fast as I could.
我都不知道是该生气还是该自豪
I don't know whether to be angry or proud.
-你跟哪些朋友在一起啊  -这不重要
- What friends were you with? - It doesn't matter.
当然重要了  我不想你
Of course it matters. I don't
-跟那类人...  -我跟谁在一起你别管
- want you ha... - Who I was with is off the table.
我不会出卖他们的
I'm not gonna narc on them.
还是
Again...
又生气又自豪
angry and proud.
只有一个问题
One question, though.
你要是什么都没拿
If you didn't take anything,
干嘛觉得有责任还钱呢
why did you feel responsible?
他们是我的朋友啊
Because they're my friends.
总得有人负这个责
I guess somebody had to.
这么做是对的
It was the right thing to do.
你不觉得
Don't you think
-该是他们付钱  -爸爸
- they should be the ones paying... -Dad.
你干嘛要跟这样的女孩做朋友呢
Why are you even friends with these girls in the first place?
事情不是那么简单的
It's not that simple.
那倒是啊
No, you're right.
从来都不简单
It never is, is it?
-抱歉  -没关系  贝克特探长
- Oh, sorry. - Uh, no, Detective Beckett,
别走  我刚要回去呢
stay. I was just leaving.
不会有下次了  爸爸
It won't happen again, dad.
我保证
Promise.
你没事吧
You okay?
有时候  无知是福啊
Sometimes, ignorance is bliss.
可不是嘛
Yeah, tell me about it.
那是鉴证组的报告吗
Is that the C.S.U. report?
座椅控制键上有两组指纹
Two sets of prints on the seat controls.
奥蒂斯的指纹在前移键上
Otis' are on the seat up button.
-后移键上呢  -自己看吧
- And on the seat back? - Take a look for yourself.
你开玩笑的吧
You gotta be kidding me.
这是我们从莱拉·埃迪森车上
This is the fingerprint that we pulled
的座椅控制键上取下来的指纹
off Lyla Addison's car seat controls,
这是我们记录在案的你的指纹
and this is your fingerprint that we have on file.
他们相匹配
They are a match.
-肯定出错了  -没什么错
- There must be some mistake. - There is no mistake.
莱拉·埃迪森被杀当晚
You were in Lyla Addison's car the
-你在她的车里  -我都不认识莱拉
- night that she was killed. - I didn't even know Lyla.
你认识
Yeah, you did.
我们把你的照片给一些人看
We showed your picture around.
你在奇异七吧做酒保
You're a bartender at the Kiwi Seven Lounge.
你的工资都是不入账的现金
They pay you under the table, cash.
而莱拉是匿名股东  你还要继续说
Lyla's a silent partner. You still want to go
你不认识她吗
with the story that you don't know her?
我觉得是你杀了她
I think that you killed her,
然后把她的尸体丢在后备箱里
and then you dumped her body in her trunk.
你却没想到自己会那么内疚
What you didn't count on was the guilt.
你得一吐为快  所以你告诉了乔
You had to get it off your chest, so you told Joe,
但你的哥哥是个可敬的人
but your brother, he was an honorable man.
他不想告发你
He wasn't gonna rat you out,
但他也不想让无辜的人终身监禁
but he wasn't gonna let an innocent man go to jail for life.
所以他打电话给地检官
So he called the D.A.
但那不管用  他就买进陪审团
When that didn't work, he got on the jury.
但是你  你发现了
But you... you found out.
你意识到
And you realized...
只要他活着你就不安全
you wouldn't be safe as long as he was alive.
你就潜进他家里
And then you slipped into his apartment
在他的药里放入了氰化物
and you dosed his meds with cyanide.
-下毒  -你真是坏的跟该隐有一拼了
- Dosed his meds? - Making you the worst brother since Cain.
事情不是那样的
That isn't what happened.
那到底怎么回事
Then what happened?
好吧
Okay.
等等
Well, wait.
Wait!
我是在那没错  可我没杀她
I was there, but I didn't kill her.
我也没杀我哥哥
And I didn't kill my brother.
可不管我说什么
But it doesn't really matter what I say,
你都不会信了
you won't believe me anyway.
鉴于你另外一个选择是一级谋杀的指控
Well, considering your other choice is murder one,
你还是说说看吧
I would roll the dice.
史蒂芬才是凶手
Stephen killed Lyla.
她哥  史蒂芬·埃迪森
Stephen Addison... Her brother.
我们提到过乔的情况
And we had talked about Joe's condition.
史蒂芬定是看到乔是陪审员
Stephen must have seen Joe on that jury
就把他也杀了
and killed him, too.
史蒂芬和莱拉就是被宠坏的富二代
Stephen and Lyla were a pair of rich, spoiled coke fiends
想要去吸毒  就找我开车
who needed to make a drug run, so they had me drive.
史蒂芬在玩那把枪
Stephen's screwing around with this gun.
那个有信托基金的王八蛋觉得自己很牛
This little trust-fund gangster thinks he's so badass
后来车颠了一下  枪走火了
till we hit a pothole, and bang!
射中了莱拉
The gun went off and hit Lyla.
她当场就死了
She died instantly.
我就傻了
I freaked.
但史蒂芬威胁说如果我告密
But Stephen threatened to point the finger at me
他就指认我是凶手
if I told the truth.
我吓到了
I'm so scared.
我一无名小卒
I'm... I'm just a nobody.
他可有大律师罩着
He's got million-dollar lawyers!
我们把她的尸体放进了后备箱
We put her body in the trunk.
然后你把车弃了
And you dumped the car?
史蒂芬说我们把车留在贫民区
Stephen said if we left it in the ghetto,
你们会认为是劫车出了岔子
the cops would think it was a carjacking gone wrong.
然后呢
And then what happened?
我们把血衣扔进了一个垃圾桶
We tossed our bloody clothes in a dumpster.
我去筹款会找乔
And... I went to see Joe at his fund-raiser.
说了发生的事
And I told him what happened.
他说不能就这样把莱拉留在后备箱
He said we couldn't leave Lyla in a trunk like that.
但乔到那的时候
But by the time Joe got there,
警察已经抓了那黑人
the cops had already pulled over that black guy,
乔就去那垃圾桶
so Joe went to that dumpster
拿了史蒂芬的血衣做证据
and got Stephen's bloody clothes as insurance.
那就是乔送到检察官办公室的东西
That must be what Joe sent to the D.A.
一切都是我的错
It's all my fault.
哥哥死了  是我害了他
My brother's dead, and it's all my fault.
那晚史蒂芬在莱拉的酒吧
We can place Stephen at Lyla's bar that night.
但除了埃迪的证词  没有别的证据
But without physical evidence, all we have is Eddie's word.
怎么办  头儿
What do you think we should do, sir?
抱歉  探长
I'm sorry, detective.
看上去你也无能为力
Looks like there's nothing you can do.
不是吧  就这样让他逍遥法外吗
W-what are you saying, we just let him get away with it?
我有这么说吗
Did I say that?
头儿  你去哪
Uh, sir, where are you going?
找个老朋友
To see an old friend.
谁让你进来的
Hey. How'd you get in here?
用我的通行证
Used my key to the city.
喝一杯吗
You, uh, you want a drink?
我正打算开一瓶1875年的佳酿
I just got my hands on this brilliant bottle of 1875 St. Miriam.
我要那包衣服  路
I need that package, Lou.
乔·麦丘茨克给你的那个
The one Joe McUsic sent you.
你没处理掉
I know you didn't get rid of it.
那不是我认识的路易·卡耐基会做的事
It's not your style. Not the Louis Karnacki I know.
给你个忠告  罗伊
Word of advice, Roy.
别管这事了
Just... let this one pass you by.
你知道凶手是她哥吗
Did you know Lyla Addison was murdered by her brother?
做律师最重要的
First rule of being a lawyer
是别问你不想知道答案的问题
is never ask a question you don't want an answer to.
还好我不是律师
I guess it's good I'm not a lawyer.
这就是你们警察的毛病
Yeah, well, that's the problem with you cops.
你们活在黑白分明的世界里
You live on the corner of black and white.
但在这儿  这里是个灰色地带
But over here, on this side of the street, it's just gray.
你打算把罪名加给一个无辜的人
You just put an innocent man up for murder.
路  你这就你所谓的灰色地带吗
What's gray about that, lou?
得了吧  你要为奥蒂斯·威廉斯这种人
Oh, come on! You're gonna sing "Kumbaya"
伸张正义吗
for Otis Williams?
他偷窃  恶意伤害
Otis Williams, what, theft, uh, aggravated assault,
谋杀未遂  这还只是我们知道的
attempted murder... That's just the stuff we got him on.
但是莱拉不是他杀的  路
But he didn't kill Lyla, Lou. He didn't kill her.
罗伊  这是为了顾全大局
It's for the greater good, Roy.
是吗
What?
为了你能竞选市长吗
Your run for the mayor's office?
想想我当选后能做到的事情
Think of what I can do for this city when I'm elected.
竞选是需要钱的
Now... It takes money to get there,
埃迪森家族可以给我充足的竞选资金
and the Addisons are keeping the war chest well stocked.
这就是游戏规则
It's just how it's played.
你懂的
You know that.
罗伊  听我说  听着
Oh... Listen to me, Roy. Listen to me.
罗伊·蒙哥马利  你会是警察局长
Roy Montgomery, police commissioner.
一旦我当选
Now... When I am elected,
我保证会任命你
I will appoint you, I promise.
君子一言  驷马难追
You have my word on that.
想想我们可以为纽约做的事
Think of what we could do for this city.
别管这事了
You gotta let this go.
拜托
Please.
把乔·麦丘茨克给你的那个包裹给我
Give me the package Joe McUsic sent you...
我会帮你求情
and I'll put in a good word for you.
初步的实验室测试结果证实
Preliminary lab results indicate
史蒂芬的衣服上有被害者的血迹
at Stephen's clothes had Lyla's blood on it.
埃迪没骗我们
Eddie was telling the truth.
鉴证组在史蒂芬的公寓里发现了氰化物
And C.S.U. found traces of cyanide in Stephen's apartment.
年轻的埃迪森先生被控两起谋杀
Young Mr. Addison is going down for both murders...
过失杀人  杀死他妹妹
Negligent homicide for his sister.
-一级谋杀  杀死乔·麦丘茨克  -那埃迪呢
- And murder one for Joe McUsic. - What happens to Eddie?
我们会指控他事后从犯
We'll charge him with accessory after the fact,
但会争取缓刑  我去给检察官打电话
but I'll push for probation. I'll call the D.A...
市长任命的代理地检官
Well, whoever the mayor appoints as acting D.A.
我为你朋友感到惋惜
Sir, I'm sorry about your friend.
我明白
Yeah.
路的确犯了错
I mean, Lou screwed up. He did.
但不能否认他曾经的贡献
But that doesn't take away from the good he's done.
不幸的是  无论他做过多少好事
It's unfortunate that despite all that good,
人们只会记住他的这个污点
he's only gonna be remembered for this one bad thing.
你俩干得好  晚安
Well, nice work, you two. Good night.
今晚和乔什有什么活动吗
So... plans with Josh tonight?
没  他轮班
No, he's on shift.
我打算去安吉里卡看电影
I was thinking of sneaking off to the Angelika.
正在上映《禁忌星球》
"Forbidden Planet" is playing.
《禁忌星球》
"Forbidden Planet"?
是机器人的片子吗
Is, uh... is that the one with the robot?
你从没看过《禁忌星球》吗
You've never seen "Forbidden Planet"?
我看《星球大战》《黑客帝国》之类的
More of a "Star Wars," "Matrix" guy myself.
天哪
Oh, my gosh.
卡塞尔  这部电影启发了那两部
Castle, this is the movie that inspired those two.
一起去吧  就这么定了
That's it. I'm taking you.
-我请客  -可我有安排了
- My treat. - Oh, no, no. I-I, uh, I have plans.
现在没了
Nope, not anymore.
也行  我能吃糖果和爆米花吗
All right. Well, can I have, uh, candy and popcorn?
当然  卡塞尔  你肯定会喜欢的
Sure. Oh, Castle, you're gonna love this.
这是莱斯利·尼尔森
This is Leslie Nielsen
成为喜剧大师前的作品
before he became a comic genius.
-是吗  -没错
- Really? - Yeah.
看完能去雷米餐厅吃汉堡吗
Can we stop at Remy's for burgers after?
-别得寸进尺  -好吧
- Now you're pushing it. - Oh.
我开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
故事开始于二十三世纪初...
So it starts off at the beginning of the 23rd century...